<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Start on Gavin Jakubik</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/start/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Start on Gavin Jakubik</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 13 Jun 2020 21:56:27 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/start/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Switch to Visual Studio Code</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/vscodeswitch/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jun 2020 21:56:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/vscodeswitch/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After setting up my website using mostly vim in a terminal that was connected to my VPS through an ssh connection. I knew that there had to be a more efficient way to manage my projects on remote machines with my own code editor than to use FileZilla and Atom. I did some research, and VSCode seemed like the perfect option, as it is an open source project with ample community support and plenty of extensions to personalize any developer&amp;rsquo;s setup.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Making The Site</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/makingthesite/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jun 2020 15:22:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/makingthesite/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Building this website with Hugo was surprisingly easy given the ability to use themes that take care of all of the styling for you, leaving only the content creation to the site administrator. One of the problems with Hugo is that it uses static website generation, which is fast but ultimately limiting because it does not enable dynamically serving content. The next thing I hope to do is script the steps of creating a new blog post for this website. I also want to learn some markdown so that I can make my content more interesting.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
