<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<channel>
		<title>Posts on Gavin Jakubik</title>
		<link>https://gavinjakubik.me/posts/</link>
		<description>Recent content in Posts on Gavin Jakubik</description>
		<generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
		<language>en-us</language>
		<copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright>
		<lastBuildDate>Sat, 13 Jun 2020 21:56:27 +0000</lastBuildDate>
		<atom:link href="https://gavinjakubik.me/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		
		<item>
			<title>The Switch to Visual Studio Code</title>
			<link>https://gavinjakubik.me/posts/vscodeswitch/</link>
			<pubDate>Sat, 13 Jun 2020 21:56:27 +0000</pubDate>
			
			<guid>https://gavinjakubik.me/posts/vscodeswitch/</guid>
			<description>After setting up my website using mostly vim in a terminal that was connected to my VPS through an ssh connection. I knew that there had to be a more efficient way to manage my projects on remote machines with my own code editor than to use FileZilla and Atom. I did some research, and VSCode seemed like the perfect option, as it is an open source project with ample community support and plenty of extensions to personalize any developer&amp;rsquo;s setup.</description>
			<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>After setting up my website using mostly vim in a terminal that was connected to my VPS through an ssh connection. I knew that there had to be a more efficient way to manage my projects on remote machines with my own code editor than to use FileZilla and Atom. I did some research, and VSCode seemed like the perfect option, as it is an open source project with ample community support and plenty of extensions to personalize any developer&rsquo;s setup.</p>
<p>After downloading VSCode, I looked into setting myself up with extensions that would be useful and make the aestetics of my environment to my taste. The most important extension by far is the Remote - SSH one, which allows me to open and manage my projects directly on my VPS without having to use other less efficient methods. Another one of my favorite features of VSCode is the availability of a terminal in the editor, whcih makes it easy to quickly run commands and to see code at the same time as it is running in terminal. It certainly is a step up from just having three separate terminal windows open with separate ssh sessions like I have done in the past for my CS assignments.</p>
<p>This work is not the most glamorous or engaging, especially when you have a project that you really want to start on, but I feel that the amount of time it is already saving me even just to post to my own website is making it well worth my time to set up. The next thing I would like to do is learn how to use vim keybindings to effectively jump around and edit files without having to use the mouse often. This is a skill that can greatly increase my efficiency when writing and editing code.</p>
]]></content>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>Making The Site</title>
			<link>https://gavinjakubik.me/posts/makingthesite/</link>
			<pubDate>Thu, 04 Jun 2020 22:13:08 +0000</pubDate>
			
			<guid>https://gavinjakubik.me/posts/makingthesite/</guid>
			<description>Building this website with Hugo was surprisingly easy given the ability to use themes that take care of all of the styling for you, leaving only the content creation to the site administrator. One of the problems with Hugo is that it uses static website generation, which is fast but ultimately limiting because it does not enable dynamically serving content. The next thing I hope to do is script the steps of creating a new blog post for this website.</description>
			<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Building this website with Hugo was surprisingly easy given the ability to use themes that take care of all of the styling for you, leaving only the content creation to the site administrator. One of the problems with Hugo is that it uses static website generation, which is fast but ultimately limiting because it does not enable dynamically serving content. The next thing I hope to do is script the steps of creating a new blog post for this website. I also want to learn some markdown so that I can make my content more interesting.</p>
<p>Eventually, I hope to move on to simply using Hugo as a tool to start my own website off of with the html generation, and then possibly use bootstrap to customize my site further than the Hugo theme allowed. I think that scripting the motion of files in my workflow is the next big step in mastering efficiently tackling interesting problems without getting caught up in time-consuming, menial tasks.</p>
]]></content>
		</item>
		
	</channel>
</rss>
